<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
	<name>Syntho Race</name>
	<author>ChadSexington</author>
	<url>http://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=1234438466</url>
	<targetVersion>0.18.0</targetVersion>
	<description>Synthetically created humanoids, commonly called "Synthos", are often used on Glitterworlds to do the things deemed "unwanted" by the populace. They are usually attractive, as anyone on the Glitterworlds would want their servants to be.

[h1]Current Version:[/h1] [b]1.3[/b]

[b]PLEASE SEE CHANGE NOTES FOR ALL PATCHES/UPDATES[/b]

[h1]Features:[/h1]
Playable vat grown Humanoids complete with backstories. All syntho are Vatgrown as children but their adulthood is random from a small pool of jobs.
New plant, Enargo, a natual solar cell plant. Cannot be grown in hydroponics. Can only be planted by Syntho.
New Meal, Enargo Meal. Requires Enargo to make. Can be made in stacks or singles. Can only be made by Syntho.
New Power generation based on Enargo. Environmentally friendly.
New clothing
Two new melee weapons and a pistol. Craftable at the stations you would expect them to be.
Custom start Scenario
Lore friendly (albeit a bit shy on the details)
Works with existing saves (Faction won't spawn unless you have a mod for that though)
Works with EPOE and RBSE


[h1]The Stats:[/h1]
Generally speaking, Syntho are about 25% better at everything physical. 
Mental, however, they are less impressive with. They research 15% slower and learn 10% slower due to the rapid development of their bodies and brains.  
They cannot eat normal food either and require energy from Enargo.
Comfortable temperature for both Syntho and Enargo is 0C to 50C. 
They do not have parents.
They cannot enjoy or hate drugs, as they can't use them.

Glitter Pistol is extremely accurate at close range and moderately at medium but pretty bad at long range. It's also extremely light so don't bother using it as a melee weapon. High damage.
Glitter Knife is just an improved knife that's more expensive.
Glitter Sword is much the same.

[h1]Age Weight Graph[/h1]
[img]https://i.imgur.com/rP18YOH.png[/img]
They can live to about 250 years old, with most of them being between 20 and 120 years old.

[h1]Planned Features[/h1]
[list][*]More backstories - If you have suggestions please add them below.
[*]More weapons
[*]New limb attachments
[*]More food options
[*]Custom Traits and Thoughts.
[*][strike]Clothing and[/strike] armors
[*]Syntho specific production benches with items exclusive to them
[*]MORE LORE[/list]

[h1]Known Bugs[/h1]
For some reason, sometimes males spawn with twintails regardless of that hair being tagged as female only.
VR Camgirl spawns on males even though its commonality for males is set to 0 and its bodytype requirement is set to female.
Wandering pawns that join of their own free will spawn with normal backstories and parent-child relations.
Potential issue with EPOE that makes it so you can't install medical ribs on humans or androids. Unknown cause.


Hair imported from [url=http://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=725949967]Rimsenal-Rimhair[/url]</description>
</ModMetaData>